[
  {
    "question": "experiment",
    "options": [
      "aygıt",
      "kapalı",
      "deney",
      "ekseriyetle"
    ],
    "answer": "deney"
  },
  {
    "question": "equipment",
    "options": [
      "ekipman",
      "ana",
      "gelişim",
      "esnasında"
    ],
    "answer": "ekipman"
  },
  {
    "question": "end",
    "options": [
      "görmek",
      "uç",
      "iş",
      "dönmek"
    ],
    "answer": "uç"
  },
  {
    "question": "stopper",
    "options": [
      "sonuç olarak",
      "gelişim",
      "ses",
      "tıkaç"
    ],
    "answer": "tıkaç"
  },
  {
    "question": "measuring tape",
    "options": [
      "çelik şerit",
      "amaç",
      "çeşit",
      "dış"
    ],
    "answer": "çelik şerit"
  },
  {
    "question": "instructions",
    "options": [
      "çekiç",
      "pusula",
      "talimat",
      "temel"
    ],
    "answer": "talimat"
  },
  {
    "question": "pressure",
    "options": [
      "kesici alet",
      "dönüştürmek",
      "basınç",
      "çinko"
    ],
    "answer": "basınç"
  },
  {
    "question": "level",
    "options": [
      "simgelemek",
      "seviye",
      "esnek",
      "fark etmek"
    ],
    "answer": "seviye"
  },
  {
    "question": "result",
    "options": [
      "çok",
      "deney",
      "ilişkili olmak",
      "sonuç"
    ],
    "answer": "sonuç"
  },
  {
    "question": "specifications",
    "options": [
      "şartlar",
      "sünük",
      "gözlemek",
      "şimdi"
    ],
    "answer": "şartlar"
  },
  {
    "question": "to take",
    "options": [
      "almak",
      "sonunda",
      "istemek",
      "bobin"
    ],
    "answer": "almak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to fill",
    "options": [
      "sünük",
      "gerekli",
      "doldurmak",
      "kalıp"
    ],
    "answer": "doldurmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to close",
    "options": [
      "sonra",
      "şekil vermek",
      "kapatmak",
      "germek"
    ],
    "answer": "kapatmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to invert",
    "options": [
      "korozyon",
      "pil",
      "ters çevirmek",
      "kontak bileziği"
    ],
    "answer": "ters çevirmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to place",
    "options": [
      "yerleştirmek",
      "dövülebilirlik",
      "kararma",
      "bileşen"
    ],
    "answer": "yerleştirmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to hold",
    "options": [
      "dar",
      "almak",
      "kuvvet",
      "tutmak"
    ],
    "answer": "tutmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to let",
    "options": [
      "bırakmak",
      "geliştirmek",
      "kapalı",
      "dikkatlice"
    ],
    "answer": "bırakmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to write down",
    "options": [
      "görmek",
      "ince",
      "kaydetmek",
      "pirinç"
    ],
    "answer": "kaydetmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to follow",
    "options": [
      "demek",
      "kısım",
      "dalga",
      "izlemek"
    ],
    "answer": "izlemek"
  },
  {
    "question": "closed",
    "options": [
      "kapalı",
      "dar",
      "pahalı",
      "herhangi bir"
    ],
    "answer": "kapalı"
  },
  {
    "question": "full",
    "options": [
      "önem",
      "nadir",
      "gerilme",
      "dolu"
    ],
    "answer": "dolu"
  },
  {
    "question": "narrow",
    "options": [
      "dar",
      "şekil vermek",
      "vermek",
      "iş"
    ],
    "answer": "dar"
  },
  {
    "question": "completely",
    "options": [
      "sonunda",
      "tamamen",
      "çatlamak",
      "dövülebilirlik"
    ],
    "answer": "tamamen"
  },
  {
    "question": "carefully",
    "options": [
      "dikkatlice",
      "iş",
      "tel",
      "bırakmak"
    ],
    "answer": "dikkatlice"
  },
  {
    "question": "vertically",
    "options": [
      "dikey olarak",
      "tahta",
      "çeşit",
      "uzay"
    ],
    "answer": "dikey olarak"
  },
  {
    "question": "current",
    "options": [
      "şekil vermek",
      "en iyi",
      "akım",
      "yön"
    ],
    "answer": "akım"
  },
  {
    "question": "power plant",
    "options": [
      "elektrik santrali",
      "iletken",
      "gerilme kuvveti",
      "pahalı"
    ],
    "answer": "elektrik santrali"
  },
  {
    "question": "magnet",
    "options": [
      "kesici alet",
      "elde etmek",
      "mıknatıs",
      "insan"
    ],
    "answer": "mıknatıs"
  },
  {
    "question": "coil",
    "options": [
      "deney",
      "ağır",
      "bobin",
      "bağlamak"
    ],
    "answer": "bobin"
  },
  {
    "question": "pole",
    "options": [
      "ekseriyetle",
      "kutup",
      "fark etmek",
      "…e göre"
    ],
    "answer": "kutup"
  },
  {
    "question": "line",
    "options": [
      "hat",
      "kiriş",
      "eğer",
      "gözlem"
    ],
    "answer": "hat"
  },
  {
    "question": "force",
    "options": [
      "sonuç olarak",
      "ışık",
      "iletim",
      "kuvvet"
    ],
    "answer": "kuvvet"
  },
  {
    "question": "field",
    "options": [
      "alan",
      "sonuç",
      "üst",
      "en iyi"
    ],
    "answer": "alan"
  },
  {
    "question": "circuit",
    "options": [
      "yukarı",
      "devre",
      "kaydetmek",
      "yapı"
    ],
    "answer": "devre"
  },
  {
    "question": "flow",
    "options": [
      "bileşen",
      "akış",
      "doğa",
      "olay"
    ],
    "answer": "akış"
  },
  {
    "question": "direction",
    "options": [
      "gibi",
      "yön",
      "beton",
      "çekiç"
    ],
    "answer": "yön"
  },
  {
    "question": "alternating current",
    "options": [
      "yoğunluk",
      "değişken akım",
      "daha sonra",
      "kesici alet"
    ],
    "answer": "değişken akım"
  },
  {
    "question": "collector ring",
    "options": [
      "dolu",
      "kontak bileziği",
      "boşluk",
      "çeşit"
    ],
    "answer": "kontak bileziği"
  },
  {
    "question": "to rotate",
    "options": [
      "dönmek",
      "yapı",
      "kristal halinde",
      "şekil vermek"
    ],
    "answer": "dönmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to insulate",
    "options": [
      "yalıtmak",
      "demek",
      "hemen hemen",
      "vermek"
    ],
    "answer": "yalıtmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to cut",
    "options": [
      "kesmek",
      "gibi",
      "kaydetmek",
      "vermek"
    ],
    "answer": "kesmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to cause",
    "options": [
      "ters çevirmek",
      "sebep olmak",
      "beton",
      "sonra"
    ],
    "answer": "sebep olmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to reverse",
    "options": [
      "çelik şerit",
      "geri çevirmek",
      "kuvvet",
      "dikey olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "geri çevirmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to induce",
    "options": [
      "farklı olmak",
      "bulunmak",
      "kutup",
      "endüklemek"
    ],
    "answer": "endüklemek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to connect",
    "options": [
      "kabuk",
      "bağlamak",
      "yapım",
      "fiyat"
    ],
    "answer": "bağlamak"
  },
  {
    "question": "basic",
    "options": [
      "gerekmek",
      "dayanmak",
      "saptamak",
      "temel"
    ],
    "answer": "temel"
  },
  {
    "question": "twice",
    "options": [
      "talimat",
      "olay",
      "dökme demir",
      "iki kere"
    ],
    "answer": "iki kere"
  },
  {
    "question": "external",
    "options": [
      "tip",
      "katmak",
      "yoğun",
      "dış"
    ],
    "answer": "dış"
  },
  {
    "question": "by means of",
    "options": [
      "ile",
      "direnç",
      "tepe",
      "ilk olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "ile"
  },
  {
    "question": "either...or...",
    "options": [
      "gitmek",
      "mümkün",
      "ya…ya…",
      "gözlem"
    ],
    "answer": "ya…ya…"
  },
  {
    "question": "scientist",
    "options": [
      "yapmak",
      "geri çevirmek",
      "muhtemelen",
      "bilim insanı"
    ],
    "answer": "bilim insanı"
  },
  {
    "question": "observation",
    "options": [
      "ana",
      "gözlem",
      "çıkarmak",
      "dikey olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "gözlem"
  },
  {
    "question": "column",
    "options": [
      "kurşun",
      "sütun",
      "büyük",
      "kapatmak"
    ],
    "answer": "sütun"
  },
  {
    "question": "to notice",
    "options": [
      "buluş",
      "fark etmek",
      "çeşit",
      "…den farklı olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "fark etmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to drop",
    "options": [
      "çok",
      "korozyon",
      "çıkarmak",
      "düşmek"
    ],
    "answer": "düşmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to observe",
    "options": [
      "gözlemek",
      "sonuç olarak",
      "havuz",
      "görmek"
    ],
    "answer": "gözlemek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to realize",
    "options": [
      "sebep olmak",
      "çatlamak",
      "…e göre",
      "anlamak"
    ],
    "answer": "anlamak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to discover",
    "options": [
      "kısım",
      "kiriş",
      "insan",
      "bulmak"
    ],
    "answer": "bulmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "while",
    "options": [
      "iken",
      "kullanım",
      "kristal halinde",
      "amaç"
    ],
    "answer": "iken"
  },
  {
    "question": "description",
    "options": [
      "ibre",
      "elektrik santrali",
      "uç",
      "tanım"
    ],
    "answer": "tanım"
  },
  {
    "question": "vacuum",
    "options": [
      "akım",
      "belirli",
      "iletmek",
      "boşluk"
    ],
    "answer": "boşluk"
  },
  {
    "question": "part",
    "options": [
      "kısım",
      "üst",
      "yol açmak",
      "devre"
    ],
    "answer": "kısım"
  },
  {
    "question": "about",
    "options": [
      "kalay",
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "iken",
      "aşağı yukarı"
    ],
    "answer": "aşağı yukarı"
  },
  {
    "question": "now",
    "options": [
      "saf",
      "kesici alet",
      "sonuç olarak",
      "şimdi"
    ],
    "answer": "şimdi"
  },
  {
    "question": "to fall",
    "options": [
      "durmak",
      "bırakmak",
      "kırılmak",
      "düşmek"
    ],
    "answer": "düşmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to form",
    "options": [
      "şartlar",
      "oluşmak",
      "yaklaşık olarak",
      "merkezi"
    ],
    "answer": "oluşmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to remove",
    "options": [
      "kalay",
      "sonuç",
      "çıkarmak",
      "ısı"
    ],
    "answer": "çıkarmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to stop",
    "options": [
      "sütun",
      "herhangi bir",
      "durmak",
      "tamamen"
    ],
    "answer": "durmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to support",
    "options": [
      "dönüştürmek",
      "desteklemek",
      "bobin",
      "doğa"
    ],
    "answer": "desteklemek"
  },
  {
    "question": "upper",
    "options": [
      "çelik şerit",
      "üst",
      "dayanmak",
      "insan"
    ],
    "answer": "üst"
  },
  {
    "question": "heavy",
    "options": [
      "gerçekten",
      "elde etmek",
      "ağır",
      "hesaplamak"
    ],
    "answer": "ağır"
  },
  {
    "question": "first",
    "options": [
      "ilk olarak",
      "çok",
      "seçmek",
      "çatlamak"
    ],
    "answer": "ilk olarak"
  },
  {
    "question": "then",
    "options": [
      "daha sonra",
      "ekseriyetle",
      "uzay",
      "tepe"
    ],
    "answer": "daha sonra"
  },
  {
    "question": "next",
    "options": [
      "sonra",
      "yukarı",
      "katmak",
      "bilim insanı"
    ],
    "answer": "sonra"
  },
  {
    "question": "finally",
    "options": [
      "sonunda",
      "çeşit",
      "çizmek",
      "izlemek"
    ],
    "answer": "sonunda"
  },
  {
    "question": "as a result",
    "options": [
      "sonuç olarak",
      "ortam",
      "esnek",
      "son derece"
    ],
    "answer": "sonuç olarak"
  },
  {
    "question": "man",
    "options": [
      "kısa bir süre sonra",
      "kapalı",
      "iş",
      "insan"
    ],
    "answer": "insan"
  },
  {
    "question": "world",
    "options": [
      "dayanmak",
      "gitmek",
      "uzay",
      "dünya"
    ],
    "answer": "dünya"
  },
  {
    "question": "coat of tarnish",
    "options": [
      "gibi",
      "kararma",
      "kontak bileziği",
      "içinden"
    ],
    "answer": "kararma"
  },
  {
    "question": "conductor",
    "options": [
      "vermek",
      "sınıflandırmak",
      "düşmek",
      "iletken"
    ],
    "answer": "iletken"
  },
  {
    "question": "manufacture",
    "options": [
      "esnasında",
      "büyük",
      "yapım",
      "basınç"
    ],
    "answer": "yapım"
  },
  {
    "question": "brass",
    "options": [
      "tıkaç",
      "gözlem",
      "mümkün",
      "pirinç"
    ],
    "answer": "pirinç"
  },
  {
    "question": "to find",
    "options": [
      "tepe",
      "gerilme",
      "bulmak",
      "özgün"
    ],
    "answer": "bulmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to be located",
    "options": [
      "bulunmak",
      "gerekmek",
      "bağlamak",
      "yukarı"
    ],
    "answer": "bulunmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to cover",
    "options": [
      "ilk",
      "kaplamak",
      "olay",
      "şimdi"
    ],
    "answer": "kaplamak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to add",
    "options": [
      "katmak",
      "aygıt",
      "farklı olmak",
      "pil"
    ],
    "answer": "katmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "all over",
    "options": [
      "aşağı yukarı",
      "boşluk",
      "her yerde",
      "korozyon"
    ],
    "answer": "her yerde"
  },
  {
    "question": "next to",
    "options": [
      "iki kere",
      "bileşen",
      "çok",
      "yanında"
    ],
    "answer": "yanında"
  },
  {
    "question": "pure",
    "options": [
      "sütun",
      "aşağı",
      "saf",
      "esnek"
    ],
    "answer": "saf"
  },
  {
    "question": "dense",
    "options": [
      "büyük",
      "tahta",
      "içinden",
      "yoğun"
    ],
    "answer": "yoğun"
  },
  {
    "question": "probably",
    "options": [
      "hız",
      "…dan önce",
      "saf",
      "muhtemelen"
    ],
    "answer": "muhtemelen"
  },
  {
    "question": "extremely",
    "options": [
      "tanım",
      "gerekli",
      "doğa",
      "son derece"
    ],
    "answer": "son derece"
  },
  {
    "question": "in fact",
    "options": [
      "iletmek",
      "çizmek",
      "çekmek",
      "gerçekten"
    ],
    "answer": "gerçekten"
  },
  {
    "question": "vibration",
    "options": [
      "kalay",
      "yapım",
      "titreşim",
      "son derece"
    ],
    "answer": "titreşim"
  },
  {
    "question": "speed",
    "options": [
      "uzay",
      "hız",
      "buluş",
      "yol açmak"
    ],
    "answer": "hız"
  },
  {
    "question": "medium",
    "options": [
      "ışık",
      "kalıp",
      "ortam",
      "dikey olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "ortam"
  },
  {
    "question": "velocity",
    "options": [
      "gerilme",
      "pusula",
      "hız",
      "sebep olmak"
    ],
    "answer": "hız"
  },
  {
    "question": "space",
    "options": [
      "kolayca",
      "dökme demir",
      "yukarı",
      "uzay"
    ],
    "answer": "uzay"
  },
  {
    "question": "through",
    "options": [
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "germek",
      "özellik",
      "içinden"
    ],
    "answer": "içinden"
  },
  {
    "question": "to differ",
    "options": [
      "iken",
      "mühendislik",
      "önemli",
      "farklı olmak"
    ],
    "answer": "farklı olmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to travel",
    "options": [
      "çelik şerit",
      "gitmek",
      "bırakmak",
      "ekipman"
    ],
    "answer": "gitmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to calculate",
    "options": [
      "kapalı",
      "tamamen",
      "izlemek",
      "hesaplamak"
    ],
    "answer": "hesaplamak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to call",
    "options": [
      "ampul",
      "demek",
      "çıkarmak",
      "yapmak"
    ],
    "answer": "demek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to know",
    "options": [
      "bilmek",
      "esnasında",
      "ana",
      "üretmek"
    ],
    "answer": "bilmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to need",
    "options": [
      "ekipman",
      "gerekmek",
      "muhtemelen",
      "dar"
    ],
    "answer": "gerekmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "any",
    "options": [
      "almak",
      "kullanım",
      "herhangi bir",
      "iyi bilinen"
    ],
    "answer": "herhangi bir"
  },
  {
    "question": "important",
    "options": [
      "vermek",
      "oluşmak",
      "çeşit",
      "önemli"
    ],
    "answer": "önemli"
  },
  {
    "question": "much",
    "options": [
      "tamamen",
      "çok",
      "yön",
      "nadir"
    ],
    "answer": "çok"
  },
  {
    "question": "about (approx.)",
    "options": [
      "ilk olarak",
      "pirinç",
      "yaklaşık olarak",
      "dikkatlice"
    ],
    "answer": "yaklaşık olarak"
  },
  {
    "question": "easily",
    "options": [
      "şartlar",
      "desteklemek",
      "makine",
      "kolayca"
    ],
    "answer": "kolayca"
  },
  {
    "question": "cutting tool",
    "options": [
      "kesici alet",
      "düşmek",
      "iletken",
      "sünük"
    ],
    "answer": "kesici alet"
  },
  {
    "question": "die",
    "options": [
      "şartlar",
      "kalıp",
      "kutup",
      "iletim"
    ],
    "answer": "kalıp"
  },
  {
    "question": "light bulb",
    "options": [
      "pil",
      "ampul",
      "havuz",
      "makine"
    ],
    "answer": "ampul"
  },
  {
    "question": "resistance",
    "options": [
      "kuvvet",
      "yanında",
      "direnç",
      "bırakmak"
    ],
    "answer": "direnç"
  },
  {
    "question": "corrosion",
    "options": [
      "şekil vermek",
      "korozyon",
      "geliştirmek",
      "dayanmak"
    ],
    "answer": "korozyon"
  },
  {
    "question": "rare",
    "options": [
      "nadir",
      "seviye",
      "iyi bilinen",
      "dökme demir"
    ],
    "answer": "nadir"
  },
  {
    "question": "expensive",
    "options": [
      "izlemek",
      "farklı olmak",
      "herhangi bir",
      "pahalı"
    ],
    "answer": "pahalı"
  },
  {
    "question": "almost",
    "options": [
      "hemen hemen",
      "yoğun",
      "gerekmek",
      "kabuk"
    ],
    "answer": "hemen hemen"
  },
  {
    "question": "phenomenon",
    "options": [
      "ekipman",
      "malzeme",
      "olay",
      "buluş"
    ],
    "answer": "olay"
  },
  {
    "question": "principle",
    "options": [
      "anlamak",
      "…dan önce",
      "ilke",
      "tip"
    ],
    "answer": "ilke"
  },
  {
    "question": "discovery",
    "options": [
      "buluş",
      "gözlemek",
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "tutmak"
    ],
    "answer": "buluş"
  },
  {
    "question": "development",
    "options": [
      "iken",
      "gelişim",
      "çok",
      "gerekmek"
    ],
    "answer": "gelişim"
  },
  {
    "question": "device",
    "options": [
      "aygıt",
      "ya…ya…",
      "çinko",
      "düşmek"
    ],
    "answer": "aygıt"
  },
  {
    "question": "importance",
    "options": [
      "malzeme",
      "bırakmak",
      "önem",
      "yapım"
    ],
    "answer": "önem"
  },
  {
    "question": "to lead to",
    "options": [
      "yol açmak",
      "dayanmak",
      "durmak",
      "fiyat"
    ],
    "answer": "yol açmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to see",
    "options": [
      "gerilme kuvveti",
      "kesici alet",
      "görmek",
      "elektrik santrali"
    ],
    "answer": "görmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to obtain",
    "options": [
      "elde etmek",
      "saf",
      "gerilme kuvveti",
      "sonunda"
    ],
    "answer": "elde etmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "according to",
    "options": [
      "…e göre",
      "içinden",
      "kuvvet",
      "gerilme"
    ],
    "answer": "…e göre"
  },
  {
    "question": "lustre",
    "options": [
      "parlaklık",
      "yay",
      "anlamak",
      "iletmek"
    ],
    "answer": "parlaklık"
  },
  {
    "question": "conductivity",
    "options": [
      "durmak",
      "iletkenlik",
      "pahalı",
      "korumak"
    ],
    "answer": "iletkenlik"
  },
  {
    "question": "ability",
    "options": [
      "yetenek",
      "önemli",
      "iyi bilinen",
      "gerçekten"
    ],
    "answer": "yetenek"
  },
  {
    "question": "structure",
    "options": [
      "deney",
      "yapı",
      "dalga",
      "basınç"
    ],
    "answer": "yapı"
  },
  {
    "question": "crust",
    "options": [
      "doğa",
      "beton",
      "kabuk",
      "elde etmek"
    ],
    "answer": "kabuk"
  },
  {
    "question": "hardness",
    "options": [
      "saptamak",
      "sertlik",
      "bileşen",
      "kurşun"
    ],
    "answer": "sertlik"
  },
  {
    "question": "density",
    "options": [
      "gerekmek",
      "görünmek",
      "dayanmak",
      "yoğunluk"
    ],
    "answer": "yoğunluk"
  },
  {
    "question": "purpose",
    "options": [
      "sütun",
      "sonuç olarak",
      "tıkaç",
      "amaç"
    ],
    "answer": "amaç"
  },
  {
    "question": "strength",
    "options": [
      "korumak",
      "mukavemet",
      "dış",
      "durmak"
    ],
    "answer": "mukavemet"
  },
  {
    "question": "price",
    "options": [
      "dönmek",
      "fiyat",
      "şekil vermek",
      "yapım"
    ],
    "answer": "fiyat"
  },
  {
    "question": "crystalline",
    "options": [
      "kısa bir süre sonra",
      "ince",
      "kristal halinde",
      "tel"
    ],
    "answer": "kristal halinde"
  },
  {
    "question": "wave",
    "options": [
      "dar",
      "dalga",
      "önem",
      "ilişkili olmak"
    ],
    "answer": "dalga"
  },
  {
    "question": "phenomena",
    "options": [
      "olaylar",
      "çekilebilirlik",
      "olay",
      "insan"
    ],
    "answer": "olaylar"
  },
  {
    "question": "nature",
    "options": [
      "ekseriyetle",
      "doğa",
      "iletkenlik",
      "çatlamak"
    ],
    "answer": "doğa"
  },
  {
    "question": "transmission",
    "options": [
      "iletim",
      "çinko",
      "ilişkili olmak",
      "ortam"
    ],
    "answer": "iletim"
  },
  {
    "question": "kind",
    "options": [
      "parlaklık",
      "çeşit",
      "ya…ya…",
      "tutmak"
    ],
    "answer": "çeşit"
  },
  {
    "question": "stone",
    "options": [
      "çelik şerit",
      "kararma",
      "taş",
      "kesici alet"
    ],
    "answer": "taş"
  },
  {
    "question": "pool",
    "options": [
      "iken",
      "belirli",
      "havuz",
      "yön"
    ],
    "answer": "havuz"
  },
  {
    "question": "light",
    "options": [
      "sonunda",
      "hız",
      "ışık",
      "ibre"
    ],
    "answer": "ışık"
  },
  {
    "question": "heat",
    "options": [
      "tahta",
      "dönmek",
      "ısı",
      "demek"
    ],
    "answer": "ısı"
  },
  {
    "question": "sound",
    "options": [
      "farklı olmak",
      "yapım",
      "ses",
      "içinden"
    ],
    "answer": "ses"
  },
  {
    "question": "crest",
    "options": [
      "parlaklık",
      "çizmek",
      "tepe",
      "kapatmak"
    ],
    "answer": "tepe"
  },
  {
    "question": "distance",
    "options": [
      "germek",
      "pahalı",
      "kutup",
      "uzaklık"
    ],
    "answer": "uzaklık"
  },
  {
    "question": "to appear",
    "options": [
      "özellik",
      "görünmek",
      "yerleştirmek",
      "doldurmak"
    ],
    "answer": "görünmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to transmit",
    "options": [
      "iletmek",
      "sınıflandırmak",
      "ampul",
      "elektrik santrali"
    ],
    "answer": "iletmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to represent",
    "options": [
      "ampul",
      "insan",
      "simgelemek",
      "dar"
    ],
    "answer": "simgelemek"
  },
  {
    "question": "by",
    "options": [
      "iki kere",
      "ile",
      "bilim insanı",
      "demek"
    ],
    "answer": "ile"
  },
  {
    "question": "per",
    "options": [
      "farklı olmak",
      "bobin",
      "(saniye)de",
      "ters çevirmek"
    ],
    "answer": "(saniye)de"
  },
  {
    "question": "central",
    "options": [
      "mühendislik",
      "becermek",
      "merkezi",
      "ışık"
    ],
    "answer": "merkezi"
  },
  {
    "question": "soon",
    "options": [
      "yetenek",
      "bilmek",
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "kısa bir süre sonra"
    ],
    "answer": "kısa bir süre sonra"
  },
  {
    "question": "really",
    "options": [
      "gerçekten",
      "kurşun",
      "çıkarmak",
      "yapmak"
    ],
    "answer": "gerçekten"
  },
  {
    "question": "up",
    "options": [
      "endüklemek",
      "kesici alet",
      "kullanım",
      "yukarı"
    ],
    "answer": "yukarı"
  },
  {
    "question": "down",
    "options": [
      "yerleştirmek",
      "akım",
      "aşağı",
      "tutmak"
    ],
    "answer": "aşağı"
  },
  {
    "question": "engineering",
    "options": [
      "özgün",
      "insan",
      "mühendislik",
      "ibre"
    ],
    "answer": "mühendislik"
  },
  {
    "question": "material",
    "options": [
      "ana",
      "aşağı yukarı",
      "görmek",
      "malzeme"
    ],
    "answer": "malzeme"
  },
  {
    "question": "job",
    "options": [
      "şartlar",
      "katmak",
      "iş",
      "yaklaşık olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "iş"
  },
  {
    "question": "property",
    "options": [
      "görünmek",
      "tepe",
      "cam",
      "özellik"
    ],
    "answer": "özellik"
  },
  {
    "question": "type",
    "options": [
      "tip",
      "geri çevirmek",
      "seçmek",
      "uzay"
    ],
    "answer": "tip"
  },
  {
    "question": "machine",
    "options": [
      "çok",
      "dalga",
      "sütun",
      "makine"
    ],
    "answer": "makine"
  },
  {
    "question": "component",
    "options": [
      "zor",
      "iken",
      "bileşen",
      "çizmek"
    ],
    "answer": "bileşen"
  },
  {
    "question": "use",
    "options": [
      "kırılmak",
      "hız",
      "kullanım",
      "deney"
    ],
    "answer": "kullanım"
  },
  {
    "question": "if",
    "options": [
      "eğer",
      "ilişkili olmak",
      "ışık",
      "iyi bilinen"
    ],
    "answer": "eğer"
  },
  {
    "question": "such as",
    "options": [
      "geliştirmek",
      "doğa",
      "gibi",
      "basınç"
    ],
    "answer": "gibi"
  },
  {
    "question": "to want",
    "options": [
      "kesici alet",
      "ya…ya…",
      "kapatmak",
      "istemek"
    ],
    "answer": "istemek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to withstand",
    "options": [
      "iletken",
      "dayanmak",
      "bulmak",
      "çıkarmak"
    ],
    "answer": "dayanmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to conduct",
    "options": [
      "makine",
      "kararma",
      "yaklaşık olarak",
      "iletmek"
    ],
    "answer": "iletmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to make",
    "options": [
      "endüklemek",
      "sebep olmak",
      "akım",
      "yapmak"
    ],
    "answer": "yapmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to choose",
    "options": [
      "iletkenlik",
      "seçmek",
      "esnek",
      "…den farklı olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "seçmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to classify",
    "options": [
      "üretmek",
      "sınıflandırmak",
      "gibi",
      "çıkarmak"
    ],
    "answer": "sınıflandırmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to determine",
    "options": [
      "çizmek",
      "ile",
      "doldurmak",
      "saptamak"
    ],
    "answer": "saptamak"
  },
  {
    "question": "steel",
    "options": [
      "ses",
      "büyük",
      "çelik",
      "fark etmek"
    ],
    "answer": "çelik"
  },
  {
    "question": "cast iron",
    "options": [
      "dökme demir",
      "kuvvet",
      "akım",
      "hat"
    ],
    "answer": "dökme demir"
  },
  {
    "question": "lead",
    "options": [
      "alan",
      "kurşun",
      "nadir",
      "her yerde"
    ],
    "answer": "kurşun"
  },
  {
    "question": "zinc",
    "options": [
      "elde etmek",
      "dönmek",
      "çatlamak",
      "çinko"
    ],
    "answer": "çinko"
  },
  {
    "question": "tin",
    "options": [
      "taş",
      "basınç",
      "düşmek",
      "kalay"
    ],
    "answer": "kalay"
  },
  {
    "question": "glass",
    "options": [
      "dikey olarak",
      "cam",
      "gerçekten",
      "yapı"
    ],
    "answer": "cam"
  },
  {
    "question": "concrete",
    "options": [
      "yay",
      "…e göre",
      "(saniye)de",
      "beton"
    ],
    "answer": "beton"
  },
  {
    "question": "wood",
    "options": [
      "yanında",
      "gerilme kuvveti",
      "tahta",
      "mıknatıs"
    ],
    "answer": "tahta"
  },
  {
    "question": "best",
    "options": [
      "çeşit",
      "en iyi",
      "çekiç",
      "bilmek"
    ],
    "answer": "en iyi"
  },
  {
    "question": "great",
    "options": [
      "büyük",
      "ekseriyetle",
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "çekilebilirlik"
    ],
    "answer": "büyük"
  },
  {
    "question": "major",
    "options": [
      "çekiç",
      "ekipman",
      "korozyon",
      "ana"
    ],
    "answer": "ana"
  },
  {
    "question": "certain",
    "options": [
      "kapatmak",
      "belirli",
      "katmak",
      "bilmek"
    ],
    "answer": "belirli"
  },
  {
    "question": "frequently",
    "options": [
      "farklı olmak",
      "becermek",
      "dövülebilirlik",
      "ekseriyetle"
    ],
    "answer": "ekseriyetle"
  },
  {
    "question": "elasticity",
    "options": [
      "esneklik",
      "ile",
      "geliştirmek",
      "sonuç olarak"
    ],
    "answer": "esneklik"
  },
  {
    "question": "stress",
    "options": [
      "gerilme",
      "çekilebilirlik",
      "kısım",
      "iletkenlik"
    ],
    "answer": "gerilme"
  },
  {
    "question": "spring",
    "options": [
      "eğer",
      "yay",
      "gerçekten",
      "gelişim"
    ],
    "answer": "yay"
  },
  {
    "question": "beam",
    "options": [
      "hız",
      "görünmek",
      "kiriş",
      "nadir"
    ],
    "answer": "kiriş"
  },
  {
    "question": "malleability",
    "options": [
      "kapatmak",
      "dövülebilirlik",
      "kiriş",
      "muhtemelen"
    ],
    "answer": "dövülebilirlik"
  },
  {
    "question": "hammer",
    "options": [
      "çekiç",
      "esnek",
      "kesmek",
      "direnç"
    ],
    "answer": "çekiç"
  },
  {
    "question": "wire",
    "options": [
      "farklı olmak",
      "ışık",
      "tel",
      "iletmek"
    ],
    "answer": "tel"
  },
  {
    "question": "ductility",
    "options": [
      "geliştirmek",
      "çekilebilirlik",
      "kaplamak",
      "çekiç"
    ],
    "answer": "çekilebilirlik"
  },
  {
    "question": "tension",
    "options": [
      "kesmek",
      "yalıtmak",
      "gerilme kuvveti",
      "kutup"
    ],
    "answer": "gerilme kuvveti"
  },
  {
    "question": "to stretch",
    "options": [
      "çinko",
      "germek",
      "sonra",
      "uç"
    ],
    "answer": "germek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to return",
    "options": [
      "dikey olarak",
      "ya…ya…",
      "beton",
      "dönmek"
    ],
    "answer": "dönmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to keep",
    "options": [
      "korumak",
      "ya…ya…",
      "parlaklık",
      "yanında"
    ],
    "answer": "korumak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to give",
    "options": [
      "vermek",
      "içinden",
      "kalay",
      "katmak"
    ],
    "answer": "vermek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to shape",
    "options": [
      "ışık",
      "şekil vermek",
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "yapı"
    ],
    "answer": "şekil vermek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to fracture",
    "options": [
      "çatlamak",
      "alan",
      "sonuç olarak",
      "pusula"
    ],
    "answer": "çatlamak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to pull",
    "options": [
      "bağlamak",
      "kesmek",
      "mühendislik",
      "çekmek"
    ],
    "answer": "çekmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to break",
    "options": [
      "tutmak",
      "kırılmak",
      "dövülebilirlik",
      "kurşun"
    ],
    "answer": "kırılmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to scratch",
    "options": [
      "çizmek",
      "kullanım",
      "kurşun",
      "ilke"
    ],
    "answer": "çizmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "original",
    "options": [
      "şartlar",
      "yanında",
      "havuz",
      "özgün"
    ],
    "answer": "özgün"
  },
  {
    "question": "elastic",
    "options": [
      "ekseriyetle",
      "esnek",
      "merkezi",
      "taş"
    ],
    "answer": "esnek"
  },
  {
    "question": "malleable",
    "options": [
      "çok",
      "dövülebilir",
      "düşmek",
      "izlemek"
    ],
    "answer": "dövülebilir"
  },
  {
    "question": "ductile",
    "options": [
      "ekseriyetle",
      "sünük",
      "bağlamak",
      "sertlik"
    ],
    "answer": "sünük"
  },
  {
    "question": "possible",
    "options": [
      "ince",
      "ters çevirmek",
      "bilmek",
      "mümkün"
    ],
    "answer": "mümkün"
  },
  {
    "question": "thin",
    "options": [
      "hemen hemen",
      "herhangi bir",
      "ince",
      "ilk"
    ],
    "answer": "ince"
  },
  {
    "question": "difficult",
    "options": [
      "uzay",
      "zor",
      "çinko",
      "bileşen"
    ],
    "answer": "zor"
  },
  {
    "question": "necessary",
    "options": [
      "gerekli",
      "kaplamak",
      "önemli",
      "yol açmak"
    ],
    "answer": "gerekli"
  },
  {
    "question": "well-known",
    "options": [
      "beton",
      "iyi bilinen",
      "ısı",
      "saptamak"
    ],
    "answer": "iyi bilinen"
  },
  {
    "question": "unlike",
    "options": [
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "görmek",
      "oluşmak",
      "amaç"
    ],
    "answer": "…den farklı olarak"
  },
  {
    "question": "battery",
    "options": [
      "pil",
      "sünük",
      "şimdi",
      "gerilme"
    ],
    "answer": "pil"
  },
  {
    "question": "compass",
    "options": [
      "anlamak",
      "muhtemelen",
      "pusula",
      "desteklemek"
    ],
    "answer": "pusula"
  },
  {
    "question": "needle",
    "options": [
      "vermek",
      "ibre",
      "ince",
      "kiriş"
    ],
    "answer": "ibre"
  },
  {
    "question": "to manage",
    "options": [
      "istemek",
      "sertlik",
      "…den farklı olarak",
      "becermek"
    ],
    "answer": "becermek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to generate",
    "options": [
      "mühendislik",
      "fiyat",
      "saf",
      "üretmek"
    ],
    "answer": "üretmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to convert",
    "options": [
      "fark etmek",
      "tahta",
      "dönüştürmek",
      "seviye"
    ],
    "answer": "dönüştürmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to be related",
    "options": [
      "ya…ya…",
      "ilişkili olmak",
      "kutup",
      "pirinç"
    ],
    "answer": "ilişkili olmak"
  },
  {
    "question": "to send",
    "options": [
      "sünük",
      "yol açmak",
      "göndermek",
      "kesmek"
    ],
    "answer": "göndermek"
  },
  {
    "question": "to develop",
    "options": [
      "hemen hemen",
      "geliştirmek",
      "gerekmek",
      "iş"
    ],
    "answer": "geliştirmek"
  },
  {
    "question": "early",
    "options": [
      "yoğunluk",
      "içinden",
      "ilk",
      "sonunda"
    ],
    "answer": "ilk"
  },
  {
    "question": "during",
    "options": [
      "…e göre",
      "daha sonra",
      "esnasında",
      "oluşmak"
    ],
    "answer": "esnasında"
  },
  {
    "question": "before",
    "options": [
      "…dan önce",
      "almak",
      "ısı",
      "gerekmek"
    ],
    "answer": "…dan önce"
  }
]